<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Juanma Garcia</title>
    <link href="https://juanmagarcia.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://juanmagarcia.me" />
    <updated>2024-10-01T21:18:40+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Juanma Garcia</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://juanmagarcia.me</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Principles</title>
        <author>
            <name>Juanma Garcia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/principles-2/"/>
        <id>https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/principles-2/</id>
            <category term="principles"/>

        <updated>2024-10-01T21:18:01+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Over time I’ve accumulated a bunch of life principles, some I’ve developed myself, some I’ve learned as lessons others have shared. I will list a few here as I think are worth sharing. I try to have only a few as the “operating” ones though,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Over time I’ve accumulated a bunch of life principles, some I’ve developed myself, some I’ve learned as lessons others have shared. I will list a few here as I think are worth sharing.</p><p>I try to have only a few as the “operating” ones though, so I can focus on the few that are more relevant to the given point in my life.</p><p>To remember - these are not the principles I live by, these are the principles I strive to live by. There is a lot of internal subconscious programming that I’ve accumulated as part of being a human, and pretty much none of it works as per these principles. The principles are constant reminders of how I want to shape my life.</p><h3 id="core">Core principles</h3>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Be as transparent as I can</strong> - Do things because I actually want to do them. Try to avoid any instances of doing something because “it looks good” or “someone will think highly of me”.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Confront</strong> - face the things that are a problem in my life, in whichever way. Don’t avoid them. Delaying a decision forever is actually making the decision of inaction. People use this delaying to pass blame on someone/something else for decisions they don’t want to make. Don’t do this.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Remove the word “should” from my life</strong> - do things because I want to, not because I “should”. This helps with taking responsibility for your life. <em>Everything </em>I do, is because I choose to do so. Yes, even paying taxes or visiting that annoying family member a part of me doesn’t want to. When you refrain these as things you choose to do and are not forced to do, you realise you’re the <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/51642/invictus?ref=juanmagarcia.me" rel="noreferrer">master of your fate and the captain of your soul</a>.</p></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="accessory">Accessory Principles</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Act on imperfect conditions and keep moving forwards always. Don’t try to optimise everything - this is a recipe for being permanently paralysed. ACT FIRST, CORRECT COURSE LATER.</p></li>
<li><p>We’re all playing an infinite game, the game of life. You don’t “win” at it, the only thing that resembles winning it is actually enjoying the ride.</p></li>
<li><p>Allow your actions to show who you are. Originally inspired by Hugh Jackman and his father’s advice “<a href="https://tim.blog/2020/06/26/hugh-jackman/?ref=juanmagarcia.me" rel="noreferrer">your religion should be in your actions</a>“, not on a sticker. In a sport, let your performance show your status, not your clothes and gadgets.</p></li>
<li><p>If you want to develop a good relationship with someone you don’t yet know, treat them as if they were your friends already. If you keep your distance and formalities, you’re just perpetuating that.</p></li>
<li><p>“Go first” - from Gabby Reece. I first heard this on a <a href="https://tim.blog/2015/07/15/laird-hamilton-the-king-of-big-wave-surfing-plus-gabrielle-reece-and-brian-mackenzie/?ref=juanmagarcia.me" rel="noreferrer">Tim Ferriss podcast</a>. It basically means everybody wants to be kind and nice, but everybody is also scared of taking action. Being the one that “goes first” in these interactions just unlocks the good stuff for everyone.</p></li>
<li><p>Allow yourself to see other’s point of view. Exposing yourself to different cultures and ways of thinking can go a long way to help with this, but it’s always pretty powerful to try to see a situation from someone else’s eyes.</p></li>
</ul>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Overcoming negative self-talk by stealing a technique from meditation</title>
        <author>
            <name>Juanma Garcia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/overcoming-negative-self-talk-by-stealing-a-technique-from-meditation/"/>
        <id>https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/overcoming-negative-self-talk-by-stealing-a-technique-from-meditation/</id>
            <category term="thoughts"/>

        <updated>2024-10-01T21:12:05+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Here’s something that meditators all over the world use: when your mind wanders, you become aware of it, you let it go, and you come back to your breath. It’s a cycle universally accepted in meditation circles. That can happen as many times as necessary,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div>
<div>Here’s something that meditators all over the world use: when your mind wanders, you become aware of it, you let it go, and you come back to your breath.</div>
<br>
<div>It’s a cycle universally accepted in meditation circles.</div>
<br>
<div>That can happen as many times as necessary, because it’s part of the process of improving your mediation practice and reaping the rewards from it.</div>
<br>
<div>Use this idea to overcome negative self-talk.</div>
<br>
<div>Many people suffer from internal negative self-talk, telling ourselves how we’re not worthy or not good enough. I do too.</div>
<br>
<div>Some people battle with this much more than others. Some find it quite crippling. Some find it devastating for their self-worth and can’t seem to get out of that hole when they’re stuck on the cycle.</div>
<br>
<div>Many of us go to psychologists and psychiatrists to try to find where is it that this voice comes from, and who is to blame for its existence.</div>
<br>
<div>My suggestion is – do reps of letting go. Next time you’re having negative self-talk, simply become aware of it, say “that’s not true”, and come back to your life.</div>
<br>
<div>Without the need to unpack it and the need to find which of your childhood traumas is the origin of your current problems.</div>
<br>
<div>Just see it, release it, and come back to your other activities. That’s one rep.</div>
<br>
<div>You might constantly have to do this because your negative thoughts don’t go away. That’s okay. When you’re starting to meditate, your mind also wanders all the time. And that’s also okay.</div>
<br>
<div>You might say: but I still have these negative thoughts and need to keep doing it all the time.</div>
<br>
<div>That’s okay – no meditator ever reached Nirvana after a few sessions.</div>
<br>
<div>Hell, almost no meditator has ever reached Nirvana.</div>
<br>
<div>But for some reason they still reap the benefits of regular practice.</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My recipe to win the day</title>
        <author>
            <name>Juanma Garcia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/my-recipe-to-win-the-day/"/>
        <id>https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/my-recipe-to-win-the-day/</id>
            <category term="thoughts"/>

        <updated>2024-10-01T21:11:33+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm sure you've read a bunch of these posts already, and they all involve some sort of self-care ritual. Wake up, meditate, fill your gratitude journal, do your breathwork, some yoga, read some devotionals, preferably Stoic. There's nothing wrong with that. But once enough time&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div>
<div>I'm sure you've read a bunch of these posts already, and they all involve some sort of self-care ritual.</div>
<br>
<div>Wake up, meditate, fill your gratitude journal, do your breathwork, some yoga, read some devotionals, preferably Stoic.</div>
<br>
<div>There's nothing wrong with that.</div>
<br>
<div>But once enough time has gone by, you realise you're not moving the needle on what matters the most and no amount of "self-care" is going to actually create a meaningful difference.</div>
<br>
<div>My recipe is this: wake up, wash face, move a bit to wake your body up, and sit down to do the meaningful work you now you need to do.</div>
<br>
<div>That's it.</div>
<br>
<div>For movement, I literally do 15 jumping jacks. That's it. The only purpose is to shake the grogginess off. Don't start a workout. Get on your meaningful thing.</div>
<br>
<div>How long do you spend on this meaningful activity? As long as you can. Some people can do 3 hours, some people can do 5 minutes.</div>
<br>
<div>But 5 minutes is better than anything.</div>
<br>
<div>And a little time every day moving the meaning needle in your favour is a lot better than the hours you're spending thinking you're wasting your life away.</div>
<br>
<div>Give it a shot, 100 times, and let me know how it goes.</div>
<br>
<div>Godspeed.</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How I give something a worthy effort (Rule of 100)</title>
        <author>
            <name>Juanma Garcia</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/how-i-give-something-a-worthy-effort-rule-of-100/"/>
        <id>https://juanmagarcia.me/posts/how-i-give-something-a-worthy-effort-rule-of-100/</id>
            <category term="thoughts"/>

        <updated>2024-10-01T21:11:05+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I've had this "rule" for myself for quite a while and I've since heard from other people some variation of this (I think it was Alex Hormozi and Scott Galloway if I'm not wrong). I have a confession to make: I've been a chronic starter&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div>
<div>I've had this "rule" for myself for quite a while and I've since heard from other people some variation of this (I think it was Alex Hormozi and Scott Galloway if I'm not wrong).</div>
<br>
<div>I have a confession to make: I've been a chronic starter for most of my life.</div>
<br>
<div>I've started a million things, many many more than I can remember. To name a short few: German language, Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu, shorthand writing, computer science studies, industrial design studies, and many more.</div>
<br>
<div>Blame my chronic perfectionism, or my deeply entrenched fear of failure. It doesn't matter.</div>
<br>
<div>I realised that in many cases, I would say "it just wasn't for me", or "it wasn't so interesting in the end".</div>
<br>
<div>I've seen this attitude time and again in myself and others.</div>
<br>
<div>Things were not "not for me".</div>
<br>
<div>I just wasn't willing to do the work, the follow through, the consistent practice.</div>
<br>
<div>Everything is lovely and exciting the first couple of times. Then the excitement wears off, and you just have to do the work.</div>
<br>
<div>So I developed a rule: I would not be allowed to say "I tried it" unless I'd done it at least 100 times.</div>
<br>
<div>Nowadays, it's okay for me to quit doing something even if I've done it only a few times.</div>
<br>
<div>But I don't allow myself to say that "I tried".</div>
<br>
<div>I say "I didn't give it a proper effort".</div>
<br>
<div>And that's okay.</div>
<br>
<div>But I'm never again confusing a half-assed effort with "it wasn't my thing".</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
